David Walker: Front End Web Developer

Address: 31 Wellbrook Way, Girton, Cambridgeshire, CB3 0FW Phone: 07530494016 | Email: davidw1427@gmail.com

Personal Statement

Over the past 7 years I have developed a career in Web development that I am very proud ofrising from volunteering in the web sector, to Junior development to now a Lead Front End Web Developer at a successful Cambridge based digital agency.

I'm fortunate that I do not consider what I do for a living a job, but a passion- I put a lot of time into learning my craft to be the best I can be and immerse myself in projects, with attention to detail and an enjoyment for seeing individuals and businesses alike improve their online presence and connect with their target audience.

My goal is to enhance my Javascript skills further and learn more backend technologies to advance myself into the realm of full stack developer.

Employment History

Lead Front End Developer | Chameleon Studios

Cambridge | January 2013 - Present

- Responsible for the entire front end development phase of a project including integration into Content Management Systems
- HTML, SASS, Gulp, Github, Wordpress, Craft CMS, Expression Engine, SVG Animation, Javascript (mostly DOM manipulation), PHP, databases
- Setting websites live, directly helping customers and attending workshop meetings

Junior Web Developer | Phoenix Internet Consultancy

Haverhill | February 2012 - January 2013

- Began working as an unpaid volunteer in February 2012 to get web development experience
- Worked with designers to turn photoshop designs into functioning websites
- Phoenix used Joomla as the primary CMS which I gained experience in using
- Role allowed me to get a "step on the ladder" in my career in web development

Store Supervisor & Retail Assistant | WH Smith

Haverhill | November 2008 - April 2012

- Responsible for managing 3 other staff members
- Processing store banking and till reconciliation
- Public facing customer service skills
- Meeting store sales targets
- Handling stock deliveries and store displays

Technical Skills

- Languages: HTML, CSS 3, jQuery, BEM, Javascript
- Databases: MySQL
- Version Control System: Git
- Content Management Systems: Wordpress, Expression Engine, Craft
- Animations: SVG Animations
- Task Runners: GULP
- <u>Design Tools:</u> Photoshop, Figma, Sketch

Education

UK Open Learning College (2011)

• OCN Diploma in Website Design & Development.

West Suffolk College, Bury St Edmunds (2006)

• Business Studies, Administration and CLAIT.

Samuel Ward Upper School, Haverhill (2005)

- GNVQ passes in ICT and Business Studies.
- GCSE passes in Maths (C), History (C), Science Double Award (C), English Language (C), English Literature (C).
- AS Level Sociology, History and Psychology.
- Certificate in Sage Line 50.

References

I have references available, but would prefer a potential employer to contact me first to obtain these references.

Portfolio Website

davidwalker.tech